# **Ahmed Imtiaz**

#### IT ENGINEER

## **ABOUT**

I have 3+ years of experience ensuring tech peace of mind for businesses. Specializes in technical system support and have a proven track record of providing technical support in a fast-paced environments. Possessing professional training & certifications from CISCO and Microsoft. If you're looking for a support partner who brings a positive attitude and genuinely interested in helping users succeed, I'd love to connect.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### IT ENGINEER

<u>Cubezix Technologies - Dubai, UAE</u> <u>Nov 2023 - Present</u>

- Providing technical support to all the users across the business.
- Support Office 365 applications, including Outlook, SharePoint, Teams, and other associated services.
- Actively engaged with vendors for IT equipment quotations and resolve technical issues promptly, ensuring seamless operation of IT systems.
- Managing users, groups, and computers using Active Directory & deal with password/login issue
- Managing, locking & securing end user devices using SOTI MobiControl
- Installation & configuration of software applications on windows, chrome books, Tablets etc.
- Responding and resolving the support requests and service tickets in a timely manner
- Troubleshooting computer hardware, software, systems, printers and scanners
- Providing support for wireless meeting rooms such as Barco Click Share

#### TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

<u>Prima Systems - Pakistan</u> <u>Feb 2023 – Sep 2023</u>

> Provided technical support to the employees of a US based healthcare organization via phone, email, and remotely using remote support tools.



# CONTACT writetoahmedimtiaz@gmail.com 0547 690166 www.inkedin.com/in/ahmedimtiaz

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Dubai, UAE

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA) Training

#### **SKILLS**

- Hardware and software troubleshooting
- OS installation and configuration (e.g., Windows, macOS)
- AD administration
- Peripheral device support (printers, scanners, etc.)
- Office 365 Support
- Mobile device management
- Knowledge base creation and maintenance

#### **EDUCATION**

Lahore Leads University , 2018 BS Software Engineering

- Provided technical support and guidance to end-users, resolving network and software issues.
- Guiding end users on software functionalities and provided technical support.
- Installation & configuration of software applications on windows, chrome books, Tablets etc.
- Assisted in managing AD, Email accounts & deal with password/login issues
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to escalate and resolve complex technical issues.
- Use Service Now for ticket management (Assign, follow up, resolution & close).
- Documented and maintained detailed records of customer interactions, including solutions and resolutions.

#### **NETWORK & SYSTEM ENGINEER**

#### <u>FutureNow Technologies</u> <u>Jan 2022 – Jan 2023</u>

- Providing technical support to all the users' across the business.
- Managed and maintained network infrastructure, including routers, switches, firewalls, and servers, to ensure high availability.
- Troubleshot and resolved network issues, performing root cause analysis and implementing proactive measures to prevent future incidents.
- Continuous network & infrastructure monitoring using Solar Winds and PRTG
- Use Service Now for ticket management (Assign, follow up, resolution & close).
- Provided technical support and guidance to end-users, resolving hardware and software issues.
- Managing users, groups, and computers using Active Directory and Exchange Management Console
- Support Office 365 applications, including Outlook, SharePoint, Teams, and other associated services.
- Configuration & maintenance of CISCO IP phones, CCTV, IP cameras

# SYSTEMS SUPPORT ENGINEER

<u>Dunya News - Pakistan</u> <u>Apr 2021 – Dec 2021</u>

- Provided technical support and troubleshooting for software and hardware issues to minimize downtime.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, printers and scanners
- Assisted in managing AD, Email accounts & deal with password/login issues
- Responding and resolving the support requests and service tickets in a timely manner
- Assisted in troubleshooting network connectivity and hardware/software issues.